Finding Aid for Robert Eli Burroughs papers, 1941-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert Eli Burroughs papers 1941-1970
Burroughs, Robert Eli, 1904-1978.
861082 Aa 2
Burroughs was assistant director of the Engineering Research Institute, later director of its successor organization, the Research Institute [reorganized in 1961 as the Office of Research Administration (ORA)] of the University of Michigan. Papers includes topical files, correspondence, ORA executive committee minutes, and reports and proceedings of the National Conference on the Administration of Research (NCAR)
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
14 linear feet
Donor no. 6323
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Robert Eli Burroughs was born in 1904 in Everett, North Carolina. He received his B.S. degree from North Carolina State University in 1925, and his M.A. from Duke University in 1926. Following his graduation, he was employed as a researcher and physicist for Kodak Research Laboratory at Purdue University. He held this position until 1942, when he became a commander in the U.S. Navy. After World War II, Burroughs worked as the manager of several of the different research and engineering laboratories at the General Electric Company. In 1956 he came to the University of Michigan as the cost director of the Engineering Research Institute. He was soon appointed the director of the Engineering Research Institute's successor organization, the University of Michigan Research Institute. In 1962 he was appointed director of the Office of Research Administration, where he served until his retirement in 1974. He died in 1978.
The University of Michigan Research Institute was a support organization responsible for the activities of researchers in academic units across the university. It offered personnel management, proposal preparation and processing, editorial and translation, report preparation, electronic instrumentation, photographic services, a machine shop, and security and safety expertise. The Research Institute, after several reorganizations, is currently known as the Division of Research Development Administration.
The collection is arranged into four series, reflecting Burroughs' various profession engagements at the University of Michigan and other institutions: Topical files, Correspondence, Committee Minutes, and Office of Research Administration
Subjects:
Engineers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Engineering.; National Conference on the Administration of Research.; University of Michigan. Engineering Research Institute.; University of Michigan. Office of Research Administration.; University of Michigan--Research.
- Topical files 1958-1966
  Topical files is arranged alphabetically in two subseries: 1958-1965 and 1964-1966, during which time Burroughs was director of the Office of Research Administration.
  - 1958-1965
    - A-F (Box 1)
    - G-N (Box 2)
    - N-Z (Box 3)
  - 1964-1966
    - A-I (Box 4)
    - I-N (Box 5)
    - O-Z (Box 6)
- Correspondence
  Correspondence contains outgoing letters during the period 1956-1961.
  - 1956-1961 (Box 6)
    (outgoing only)
- Committee Minutes (Box 7)
  Committee Minutes contains documentation of the various committees Burroughs' participated in during his tenure at the University of Michigan. These include the Executive Committee of the Engineering Research Institute and the Administrative Staff Minutes from the Office of Research Administration.
  - Executive Committee
    - 1941-January 1948 (Box 7)
      (Department of Engineering Research)
    - February-October 1948 (Box 7)
      (Engineering Research Institute)
    - 1959-1964 (Office of Research Administration) (Box 7)
  - Administrative Staff
    - 1960-1962 (Box 7)
      (Office of Research Administration)
- Office of Research Administration
  The Office of Research Administration series contains miscellaneous files on various projects which the office managed during Burroughs' directorship. These files include development resources, annual reports, and documentation of the ORA's engagements. An alphabetically organized topic file is also contained within this series.
  - Miscellaneous Files
    - Space Research Building, October 19062-1963 (Box 8)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration Building (Box 8)
    - Nuclear Energy Building (Box 8)
    - Research Activities Building (Box 8)
    - Program and proposal development,1963-1964 (Box 8)
    - Industrial Development Office (Box 8)
    - Project 05687 (Structural Uses of Foam Plastics) (Box 8)
    - Policies and procedures (Box 8)
    - Editorial Office,1961-1962 (Box 8)
    - General,1960-1963 (Box 8)
    - Research and Equipment Committee (Box 8)
    - Articles and news releases re. ORA and research in general (Box 8)
  - Engineers Joint Council. Board of Review on National Water Policy (Box 8)
  - Annual reports,1960-1966 (Box 9)
  - Industrial grants (Box 9)
  - Program and proposal development (Box 9)
  - Publications (Research Reporter; Research News) (Box 9)
  - Appointment books (Box 9)
  - National Conference on the Administration of Research (NCAR) (Box 10)
  - Reports, proceedings, and administrative materials 1947-1970 (Box 10)
  - Topical files circa 1967-1971
    - A-C (Box 11)
    - C-M (Box 12)
    - N-R (Box 13)
    - S-Z (Box 14)
  - National Conference on the Administration of Research
    - Conference materials (Box 14)
  - Appointment calendars (Box 14)
  - Miscellanea (Box 14)